I've been running my business mentorship
now for just over a year.
I've changed, the business has changed,
and I thought this would be a good
opportunity to talk you through what I've
done to keep my business thriving,
growing, because there
are going to be a lot of things
that you can apply into your
business to do the same.
Because I've run my mentorship quite a lot
different to
all the others.
Quite a lot of people out there say, "Oh,
you've got to pay a
monthly subscription" so they can
drip-feed you amounts, and then
if you want to
leave, you get sent to court.
Others say you've got to pay like $10,000
up
front and jump on a sales call. For me,
I'm charging 2,000 US dollars.
But the funny thing is, when I began,
I charged 799.
So people in here, Ryan, for instance,
he's one of the OGs.
He got in at 799.
And I'm not mad about it because he's now
a big player in helping
other people.
He's dominated golf as a niche.
His biggest problem
is having too many clients.
Gerald Lee, he definitely got in at 799.
Katherine Sargent,
who you might have seen
that share to my story, she's one of the
799s. So you'd probably think
that I'd be annoyed that the people that
paid me barely any money at the beginning,
I'm still talking to 14 months
later. But no, and I suppose this
is the first lesson.
When you launch something,
you don't have to be expensive because you
don't really
have the leverage to be expensive.
The reason that I've increased prices over
time is that more and more people have
wanted to join.
That gives me the leverage to do so.
Now, some people are probably thinking,
"But you could have just kept it cheap."
Yes, granted. But I like the fact
that I know the majority of people in
here on a first-name basis.
If I half my prices,
I'd have to double the amount of
people coming in to make the same money,
and it would just make that very flipping
difficult. Now,
when you look at the website,
it looks like, "Oh, James has given
us lots of resources. This
is really cool." But I'll be honest,
we built the
mentorship to begin with.
I'll sign in for a sec.
And when we look at the business
mentorship modules, in the onset,
I thought this
was everything people would need.
But I also knew that if there
was anything else that people needed,
they could just
tell me because we have the Discord.
So I thought,
rather than me spending six to 12 months
building something with
stuff that people don't need,
I'm going to spend every single day in the
Discord
with people,
and if I see a trend of the same questions
appearing, to me, it goes
right. We need to build that out.
So probably three months in, I was like,
"Okay,
there seems to be a lot of onus around
short-form content." So I created
Short-Form
Content Mastery, which
is a pretty in-depth course about
mastering the art of
making short-form content.
I then thought to myself, "Hmm, what
if someone out
there doesn't want to be mentored,
doesn't want to pay 1,000 US dollars,
doesn't
want to be working inside of Discord,
they just want to get good at making
short-form content?" So we decided to sell
this on its own for 199 US dollars.
There'll be a link for
that in the description.
Then goes another two months,
spending a lot of time in the Discord,
a lot of
questions around email marketing.
So I was like, "Right,
we need to build out a course on email
marketing." So we did
that shortly afterwards.
You can tell by my haircuts how long it
took.
Then I started building out a YouTube
course.
But granted,
although that's been of great benefit to
the people in the mentorship,
I don't think it's strong enough yet to be
its own course.
Although I'd say 65% of the people in the
mentorship are PTs, I decided to make
them their own standalone course on the
pretty much basics and
fundamentals of running a PT business.
Now, if you are a personal trainer,
don't just buy Short-Form Content Mastery,
buy
the PT Starter Kit.
Link in the description.
I'll give you both.
And there's actually a bundle to get all
three of these, which we're going to do.
And you're probably going to wonder why
there's a bundle, and I'll explain.
It's now been, actually, over a year.
It's been 14 months inside this Discord.
There's the things that I've taught.
There's the things that I've learned back.
It's interesting.
I actually learn from the community
myself.
They're like, "James,
what do you think of this?
What do you think of that?" I go away,
I test it, I research it,
and I can get back
to them. I'm not like top of the pyramid,
"Do as I say." We're kind of
all working together.
I've just been at this for 10 years longer
than them.
And I've come to realize
that these actually need to be
restructured and redone,
and that's what I'm doing now.
So all of this,
I'm scrolling intentionally fast, so
you can't read it and rip it off.
It's a new course
that I've been working on for a
month,
and it's now in the process of getting
edited.
So editors are away.
We've recorded all of this.
It's why my voice has sounded quite coarse
the last few days.
Because this is how I run
and operate this mentorship.
I give you guys everything you need,
all for one, of cost, lifetime membership.
So it's worth noting that the people
that just joined the mentorship,
they've got
all these courses for free since.
If you join now,
you're going to get the next
course and the next course
and the next course. It can be 2027.
If I add a course, you're going to get it.
But my style is I know
that every six to 12 months,
this isn't good enough.
It needs to
be revamped.
I know what details I need to go into
more.
I know what walkthroughs people need.
But this isn't just like a digital course
where you get seven videos.
It's a living,
breathing organism where on an
ever-growing basis, I'm learning,
evolving,
and keeping up with the demands of the
people inside.
So think of it this way. My mentorship
is actually a community of people with
access to me. I empty these all every day.
The modules are what I create so you have
a resource to learn from so that
I don't have to handhold
and continue to teach everyone everything.
The questions I get in the Discord show me
the gaps that are in the course.
I keep building and adding to the course.
So eventually, one day,
the Discord could be quiet,
which it won't, because people
love content reviews,
which I film some of and put on socials.
So if I've piqued your interest in this
video and you're thinking, "Oh, I could
join, could join,"
if you buy one of the satellite courses
or the bundles with the
links in the description,
if you then like how I present
information, how you
learn,
if you do upgrade to the mentorship,
we will deduct the initial cost away,
so you're not penalized for buying twice.
We are looking to another price increase
coming in the following months, and there
is a brand-new mentorship going in.
And you shouldn't really tell people
that because it makes them apprehensive of
joining.
But I don't think there's any harm in
someone learning twice.
The modules are quite succinct.
You can get through the whole course in a
day.
The current price point is 1,500 pounds,
one-off fee on 1,999.
You can do the 10 weeks of one-to-one
intense for 10,000 US dollars.
A couple of people have done that.
It's been good.
I feel like I talk to them more than I
talk to my family.
And you can pay in monthly installments.
Sean Casey of Social Circle,
he's just changed his pricing model to be
the same.
I probably made the mistake of telling him
how much money I made last year.
But it's been a good year.
I see a lot of other business mentorships
running to
YouTube trying to grow their YouTube
channel.
This is what I reckon the focus should be
on for the next few years.
For review, establishing a brand,
making money, paying your bills,
growing socials,
but then slowly we want to start moving
away into long-form content.
I think that coming out the pandemic,
we've seen a trend of people being
obsessed,
this real heavily edited retention
hacking, ba-ba-ba-ba-boom.
I think people now want a little bit more
slow-paced.
Even this video, it's just me chatting.
We're having a chat.
I'm telling you about what I do.
But I think this YouTube channel
is on the edge of
maybe blowing up,
which means more people in the mentorship,
which means prices
going up.
So pretty much you can secure a position
now. Lock it in.
1,500 pound. That's not bad.
But some of these fuckers in here,
I've worked minimum
wage for them. Other people
are more self-sufficient.
So maybe this will be the push over the
edge you need to join my mentorship, or
maybe you'll wait till it gets more
expensive. You have a good day.
We had a good year. Bye-bye.